<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-11T15:11:03+00:00</updated><id>/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/feed.xml</id><title type="html">ACME RESEARCH</title><subtitle>From microbes to minds, our research bridges the hidden ecosystems of gut microbiomes with the complexities of animal intelligence.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">NERC grant award</title><link href="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2025/03/17/nerc-grant-award.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NERC grant award" /><published>2025-03-17T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-11T15:08:17+00:00</updated><id>/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2025/03/17/nerc-grant-award</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2025/03/17/nerc-grant-award.html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m excited to announce that I’ve been awarded a NERC Pushing the Frontiers of Environmental Research grant, titled “<strong>Acquisition of bene cial gut microbes and functional trade-offs in wild avian hosts</strong>”, due to begin February 2026. I will be leading the project working with Prof Lindsay Hall from the Quadram Institute. This project will pinpoint which microbes drive host fitness, uncover how they shape host phenotypes and resolve why gut microbiomes vary so widely in wildlife.</p>

<p>The NERC Pushing the Frontiers scheme funds ambitious, high-risk and high-reward projects looking at ways to help us sustain and benefit from our natural resources, predict and respond to natural hazards and understand environmental change.</p>

<p>We will be hiring to fill three positions later this year, please keep an eye out for announcements here and the University of East Anglia job opportunities website.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Gabrielle</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name>gabrielle-davidson</name></author><category term="funding" /><category term="big news" /><category term="opportunities" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I’m excited to announce that I’ve been awarded a NERC Pushing the Frontiers of Environmental Research grant, titled “Acquisition of bene cial gut microbes and functional trade-offs in wild avian hosts”, due to begin February 2026. I will be leading the project working with Prof Lindsay Hall from the Quadram Institute. This project will pinpoint which microbes drive host fitness, uncover how they shape host phenotypes and resolve why gut microbiomes vary so widely in wildlife. The NERC Pushing the Frontiers scheme funds ambitious, high-risk and high-reward projects looking at ways to help us sustain and benefit from our natural resources, predict and respond to natural hazards and understand environmental change.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Forbes</title><link href="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2024/12/03/forbes.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Forbes" /><published>2024-12-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-11T15:08:17+00:00</updated><id>/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2024/12/03/forbes</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2024/12/03/forbes.html"><![CDATA[<!-- excerpt start -->
<p>Our recent paper was featured in an article in forbes!<!-- excerpt end --></p>

<p>Our recent paper was featured in an article in forbes! It’s called “Wild Birds’ Health And Survival Is Affected By Gut Microbiome” by Grrl Scientist.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/grrlscientist/2024/12/03/wild-birds-health-and-survival-is-affected-by-gut-microbiome/">Read it here</a></p>]]></content><author><name>gabrielle-davidson</name></author><category term="article" /><category term="media" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Our recent paper was featured in an article in forbes!]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Call for citizen scientists</title><link href="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2023/04/01/citizen-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Call for citizen scientists" /><published>2023-04-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2025-04-11T15:08:17+00:00</updated><id>/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2023/04/01/citizen-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/2023/04/01/citizen-science.html"><![CDATA[<p>Attention Bird Ringers in Norfolk and Cambridgeshire! Your Expertise Needed for Scientific Research</p>

<p>Dear Fellow Bird Ringers,</p>

<p>Greetings from the Davidson Lab, University of East Anglia (UEA). Weare reaching out to request your help and expertise collecting faecal samples from GRETI. Our current project explores the gut microbiome and its potential links to cognitive behaviour in birds across urban gradients, to enhance our understanding of urban wildlife adaptation.</p>

<p>Can you collect faecal samples for us during your ringing sessions in urban/non-urban habitats, including your own garden? We are collecting samples from GRETI nestlings and adults in the spring, and adults in the winter, covering Cambridgeshire and Norfolk.</p>

<figure class="figure">
  <a class="figure-image" aria-label="figure link">
    <img src="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/images/urbangm_resize.jpg" style="
        width: 400px;
        max-height: unset;
      " alt="figure image" loading="lazy" onerror="this.src = '/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/images/fallback.png'; this.onerror = null;" />
  </a>
  
</figure>]]></content><author><name>vildan-acar</name></author><category term="citizen science" /><category term="data collection" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Attention Bird Ringers in Norfolk and Cambridgeshire! Your Expertise Needed for Scientific Research]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/urbangm.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="/ACMEresearch/preview/pr-13/urbangm.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>